[
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I update my benefit information?",
    "Answer": "You can update your benefit information online through your account.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "30eada08-5708-5c5c-9df8-0f7d5d4dc131"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What if my circumstances change?",
    "Answer": "Report changes in circumstances immediately to avoid issues.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "51fbbe84-2ac8-5daf-b0a5-8016ccd05b45"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "Can I appeal a decision?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can appeal within one month of the decision notice.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "8d000ade-6c2b-571c-aa61-5d38eb463cf8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How can I report a change in income?",
    "Answer": "Report changes in income using the online portal.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "9c92da3c-fafb-5711-b057-88cd220754b5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I stop claiming benefits?",
    "Answer": "You can stop claiming by contacting your benefit office.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6e24285d-7214-513b-86cd-9af307a992ce"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How can I apply for Universal Credit?",
    "Answer": "Apply online through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "620936fb-dd5b-565b-b612-503271a57f2a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "Where can I find job vacancies?",
    "Answer": "Check the Jobcentre Plus website for the latest job vacancies.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "89b517b8-016a-5561-873b-00ef5b2f7c9c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What help is available for job seekers?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for Jobseeker's Allowance or other support.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ecbce042-44d5-566e-b36f-a831892e284e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I prepare for a job interview?",
    "Answer": "Prepare by researching the company and practicing common interview questions.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1e6fdd08-9454-5b52-aef1-16d993251715"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the New Enterprise Allowance?",
    "Answer": "The New Enterprise Allowance helps people start their own business.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "61f1179d-b32f-590c-9bf1-53211b7f2dc3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I get sick pay if I'm self-isolating?",
    "Answer": "Yes Statutory Sick Pay is available if you're self-isolating.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1de35e0b-f233-554c-84ef-fc30494e0ea0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is Employment and Support Allowance?",
    "Answer": "ESA provides financial support if you're unable to work due to illness.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5ee4602c-ff85-54bd-a837-5c96e680fd5b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I apply for sick pay?",
    "Answer": "You need to provide a fit note from your doctor to apply for sick pay.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ecc42084-d88e-5bf0-8070-a18552c283bb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is statutory sick pay?",
    "Answer": "Statutory Sick Pay is a legal requirement for employers to pay you if you're ill.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ee6a77ec-d4ef-50f7-9762-04cc228b3a48"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I work part-time while receiving ESA?",
    "Answer": "You may be able to work part-time under the permitted work rules.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5fe283c9-4b97-55a9-a312-f9a437eb2e0b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Child Benefit?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Child Benefit online or via a postal form.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "15f4e930-a105-5d65-963b-828180f5cecd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What financial support is available for families?",
    "Answer": "Families may be eligible for Child Tax Credit and other benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "da45e8bd-bae5-5569-9971-18d7f18965ba"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "Can I get free school meals for my child?",
    "Answer": "Eligibility for free school meals depends on your income and benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f6aabeb4-ac29-501a-9c40-989a947640a5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Sure Start Maternity Grant?",
    "Answer": "The Sure Start Maternity Grant is a one-off payment to help with baby costs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "eaa7ef0a-6258-52d7-89cf-57058b82f7e5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for parental leave?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for parental leave through your employer.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6d3c7a69-456d-53e2-8b60-de32e454e382"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Personal Independence Payment (PIP)?",
    "Answer": "PIP helps with extra costs if you have a long-term health condition.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "04d2de6d-4cbe-5b27-b2e5-d1b9fa9f35e7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I apply for disability benefits?",
    "Answer": "You can apply online or by calling the Department for Work and Pensions.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "85a68cb7-c1e9-55f7-942d-48cc38baf06c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What support is available for disabled people?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for Disability Living Allowance or other benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "e7bdc104-c7d8-50d4-8857-2a01b6451126"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Attendance Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Attendance Allowance helps with extra costs if you're over State Pension age and need someone to help with personal care.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "dffeacb5-71d7-54dc-936c-1810ba4c4f82"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I get a Blue Badge?",
    "Answer": "Apply for a Blue Badge through your local council's website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ea9bc2b8-30ee-5f67-8fa8-29925ef8e522"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I get Carer\u2019s Allowance?",
    "Answer": "You can get Carer's Allowance if you care for someone for at least 35 hours a week.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "7488db67-fc5a-5ba9-85af-758fd20d3441"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What support is available for carers?",
    "Answer": "Support includes Carer\u2019s Credit and other financial aid.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "d4604027-0df3-5fed-8501-fe7e2ec8636a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I claim Carer\u2019s Credit?",
    "Answer": "Apply online or by phone to receive Carer's Credit.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f4b0a7c5-a970-5133-bd68-cfff692b57b6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is the Carer's Assessment?",
    "Answer": "The Carer's Assessment evaluates your needs as a carer and offers support.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f2c0e69d-ebf7-5f2e-9acd-e6b5db206a7f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I work while claiming Carer's Allowance?",
    "Answer": "You can work part-time while claiming Carer's Allowance as long as you don't earn over the limit.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "433fd560-f548-56ca-b0ce-1f34db8501c3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How can I apply for Income Support?",
    "Answer": "Income Support is available for people with low income who meet certain criteria.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "fa21d572-9e76-58e3-8a8d-742cc42826db"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Warm Home Discount Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Warm Home Discount Scheme offers help with energy bills.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "cf519f39-ba1f-5e92-97ef-1f93050ab238"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "Can I get help with rent?",
    "Answer": "Housing Benefit can help you pay your rent if you're on a low income.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "bd39a5c5-6df5-5b3a-b511-fbdebde67f35"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Budgeting Loan?",
    "Answer": "The Budgeting Loan helps with essential costs like furniture or rent in advance.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "0a5b1720-c6d5-5db2-a8cd-4c0f7d32822f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Council Tax Reduction?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for Council Tax Reduction through your local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ac7e8f09-e401-5c8b-8ff5-ea5de6cf07f8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What help is available for funeral costs?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Funeral Expenses Payment.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "fa67e8d5-46f3-5c29-b327-e011977d8704"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Bereavement Support?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Bereavement Support online or by phone.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6ef13152-4874-5290-953a-421e9314ea8e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I get help with inheritance tax?",
    "Answer": "There are government schemes to help with inheritance tax if you qualify.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a4850ad5-89c8-5bd6-a2f7-5eaba10234dc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is the Bereavement Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Bereavement Allowance is a weekly benefit paid to widows or widowers.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "74c18087-4d96-5823-a41b-5cb0496fb825"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I inform the government of a death?",
    "Answer": "Use the Tell Us Once service to inform multiple government agencies of a death.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "567c6d5b-14ec-50c8-b252-eb775ef0f543"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I change my payment method?",
    "Answer": "You can change your payment method by updating your account details online.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "309eb304-efa5-585e-913d-acc451941974"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What happens if I miss a payment?",
    "Answer": "If you miss a payment contact the benefit office immediately to avoid penalties.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "3574b2d2-040b-59e2-8316-9d406c6773b0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How can I get help with budgeting?",
    "Answer": "Budgeting support is available through the GOV.UK website and various charities.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "99532467-d725-50d1-afc9-22d0725c7bb6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What should I do if I\u2019ve been overpaid?",
    "Answer": "If you\u2019ve been overpaid contact the benefit office to arrange repayment.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6ae2e356-7a9c-551a-aab6-192584910e1f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I request a benefits statement?",
    "Answer": "You can request a benefits statement through your online account.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "75110a9b-480c-5ae5-919a-d4117fab7803"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How can I improve my CV?",
    "Answer": "CV improvement resources are available through Jobcentre Plus and online.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "158636c0-364b-5462-8688-53d8d08e9c9b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the Work and Health Programme?",
    "Answer": "The Work and Health Programme provides support to help you find and stay in work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a4dbb52d-5f47-5b98-8761-6d2583a449d1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "Can I get financial support while studying?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for financial support if you\u2019re studying and looking for work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a666c702-0fec-5530-b282-355b08edff41"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is a Universal Jobmatch?",
    "Answer": "Universal Jobmatch is a service that helps you find and apply for jobs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5b3c0c55-0447-51a2-a1d2-38ab7a8c72c1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I sign up for Jobseeker's Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Sign up for Jobseeker's Allowance by creating an account on the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f37d4d82-97b8-5c38-8c98-12caaf8febb8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I report a workplace injury?",
    "Answer": "Report workplace injuries to your employer and apply for compensation if eligible.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "39d45737-266e-5bbb-8d99-70edd404aa15"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is the difference between ESA and SSP?",
    "Answer": "ESA is for long-term illness or disability while SSP is for short-term sick leave.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a5030b7d-32cf-523a-ad65-c2aa88fc1f48"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How long can I receive ESA?",
    "Answer": "You can receive ESA for as long as you meet the eligibility criteria.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4991b515-854a-588e-8261-c1351713fdea"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I receive other benefits while on ESA?",
    "Answer": "Yes you may be eligible for additional benefits while receiving ESA.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "df1b86a5-3303-582a-8ff4-a2317dc1111f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is the Industrial Injuries Disablement Benefit?",
    "Answer": "This benefit supports people who have been injured or disabled at work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ee0dbb7c-f55b-53a8-94c2-2a89c2c9a0e8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "Can I claim Child Benefit if I live abroad?",
    "Answer": "You may still be eligible for Child Benefit if you live abroad under certain conditions.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "e311b3f9-a3a0-5512-a2c8-362fa87aab9f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I claim childcare costs?",
    "Answer": "You can claim back a portion of your childcare costs if you\u2019re eligible.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "dc9b7ada-9472-5daf-a96a-6e67aebac974"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Healthy Start Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Healthy Start Scheme provides vouchers to pregnant women and families with young children.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "79f157cf-9d59-54e0-bca5-d2da4e90540b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Adoption Allowance?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for Adoption Allowance through your local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4f4ceda3-c85f-5ece-ba07-768065fa2d2c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is Parental Responsibility?",
    "Answer": "Parental Responsibility is the legal right to make decisions about a child's upbringing.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a1896f5a-8fcf-50f6-8c12-990c0c1b9321"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is the Motability Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Motability Scheme helps disabled people lease a car scooter or powered wheelchair.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "3ec46063-c2ae-5243-8bce-84a0eeec4444"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I apply for a Disabled Facilities Grant?",
    "Answer": "Apply for a Disabled Facilities Grant through your local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "16824274-5202-587b-9558-968f6dabb82a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Access to Work?",
    "Answer": "Access to Work provides support and funding for disabled people in the workplace.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "06fbd2f2-64cc-5eb1-9f8f-7005bb4dc901"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "Can I get help with medical equipment?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for financial support to buy necessary medical equipment.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "bb5aca5b-05ff-5f38-a987-7bb346b2971d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Disability Premium?",
    "Answer": "Disability Premium is an additional amount added to certain benefits if you are disabled.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "428f01a5-415f-5ca3-b6c0-7d7764432b31"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is the National Carers Strategy?",
    "Answer": "The National Carers Strategy outlines the government\u2019s plan to support carers.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "c981617f-1b27-5411-9a4d-83e3bd686376"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I apply for respite care?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for respite care through your local council or care provider.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "123de8d9-54f3-5ed8-9b1c-c3efd0ad89b7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is a carer's assessment?",
    "Answer": "A carer's assessment evaluates the needs of the carer to provide appropriate support.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ba136990-385c-53dd-9683-2c5581d34167"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I receive Carer\u2019s Allowance if I\u2019m in full-time education?",
    "Answer": "You generally cannot receive Carer\u2019s Allowance if you\u2019re in full-time education.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "72fb55b4-8b98-5c50-abc0-b70507a0ae87"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I register as a carer with my GP?",
    "Answer": "Inform your GP that you are a carer and they will note it on your medical records.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6cc46743-3c46-52be-9f11-b41e1e3b8511"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is Universal Credit advance?",
    "Answer": "Universal Credit advance is a loan you can apply for if you\u2019re in financial need while waiting for your first Universal Credit payment.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f08667b8-27e4-5a5c-93c3-3a9bf15c0773"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for free school meals?",
    "Answer": "Apply for free school meals through your child's school or local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "e018f928-6330-54ac-9427-4eafa0dce1b1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Discretionary Housing Payment?",
    "Answer": "The Discretionary Housing Payment helps people with housing costs who are receiving Housing Benefit or Universal Credit.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2c3d3db0-9ce1-5d4b-94c3-8233ca685983"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "Can I get help with council tax?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Council Tax Reduction if you\u2019re on a low income.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f00ea80c-1900-519e-a3ea-9070640f96f5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Sure Start Maternity Grant?",
    "Answer": "The Sure Start Maternity Grant is a one-off payment to help with baby costs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4feb25da-47c6-5ed3-9fd5-e1acf651dfad"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I report a death?",
    "Answer": "You can report a death using the Tell Us Once service which notifies multiple government agencies.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "7562c294-07f8-59bd-8181-9685af8f886b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is the Bereavement Support Payment?",
    "Answer": "The Bereavement Support Payment helps with the financial impact of losing a partner.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "406423ef-94fb-59c0-bef9-8e5ab25d839c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I get financial help with funeral costs?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Funeral Expenses Payment if you\u2019re on a low income.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "241bfacd-0dee-5287-97b9-63fbeb514f11"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I apply for a Funeral Expenses Payment?",
    "Answer": "Apply for a Funeral Expenses Payment through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4596d69c-6be5-534e-9e0d-dd22b5b30bcc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is the Bereavement Service?",
    "Answer": "The Bereavement Service helps you report a death and check if you\u2019re eligible for benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "de58a653-e553-50ea-952c-d7e47f302310"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I appeal a benefit decision?",
    "Answer": "You can appeal a benefit decision by requesting a mandatory reconsideration within one month.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "71ed9f30-6fd4-509f-80ee-1da911c52d0a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I contact my benefit office?",
    "Answer": "You can find contact details for your benefit office on your latest correspondence or on the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "c2e2a2f0-ef75-5b28-8979-436900913928"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What happens if I\u2019m overpaid?",
    "Answer": "If you\u2019re overpaid the amount will be deducted from future payments or you\u2019ll need to repay it.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2beffe15-0f2e-5c26-87c2-e332d76eabb9"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "Can I get help with managing my benefit payments?",
    "Answer": "Yes budgeting advice and support are available through GOV.UK and local organizations.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "59ed53ce-fc72-500f-8b22-697756621ad2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What do I do if I lose my benefit card?",
    "Answer": "Report the loss immediately to your benefit office to get a replacement.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "8428c24d-69c6-554b-ad02-e92189571ec5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I claim Jobseeker's Allowance?",
    "Answer": "You can claim Jobseeker's Allowance by applying online or by phone through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "928694ba-d0bb-5866-b8ac-b6ac8b8540fd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the Work Programme?",
    "Answer": "The Work Programme is designed to help long-term unemployed people find work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "342857d0-383e-5b38-9f57-9de64ea7bbfa"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "Can I volunteer while claiming Jobseeker\u2019s Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Yes volunteering is allowed but it should not interfere with your job-seeking activities.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "c121fd0a-d566-59a9-8c39-80ad6bc423b7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the National Careers Service?",
    "Answer": "The National Careers Service offers advice and information on careers education and training.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "0946d1e7-24ed-571d-9736-ba014cf94ebc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I prepare a covering letter for job applications?",
    "Answer": "A covering letter should highlight your skills and why you\u2019re suitable for the job. Resources are available online to help.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "eab42ff8-59db-5fd3-bb86-63f74f63f569"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I claim ESA for mental health issues?",
    "Answer": "Yes Employment and Support Allowance can be claimed if mental health issues prevent you from working.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "8c02ccc9-76bb-5df4-a261-4a353010aad7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is the ESA Work Capability Assessment?",
    "Answer": "The Work Capability Assessment determines whether you are fit to work and your eligibility for ESA.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5a9b4d37-1eed-5e6c-9eaa-258cbf809034"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I get a fit note?",
    "Answer": "A fit note is provided by your doctor if you\u2019re too ill to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4006ae87-eed8-5567-a728-db002670d453"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is the difference between ESA and PIP?",
    "Answer": "ESA is for those unable to work due to illness while PIP helps with the extra costs of a long-term health condition or disability.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "39e0d687-317d-57b1-8178-7e06e4a98a58"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I claim SSP?",
    "Answer": "Statutory Sick Pay is claimed through your employer if you\u2019re too ill to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "fa497683-9615-59ea-8543-3de56ba2bc13"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Childcare Grant?",
    "Answer": "The Childcare Grant is available to students in full-time higher education who have children.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "0ea7f045-f4f7-5b70-ad4c-42369ce7f4ca"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Family Tax Credit?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Family Tax Credit through HM Revenue and Customs or the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1ad5bc7c-3e2a-5367-beee-b1c4c641d361"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "Can I get support for my child\u2019s education?",
    "Answer": "There are various grants and benefits available to support your child\u2019s education.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "8704e2a9-8571-551b-8b13-34b0a43fba2a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Child Trust Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Child Trust Fund is a long-term savings account set up for children born between 2002 and 2011.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4797e95d-6322-5c19-8734-25cfe935d9ea"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I register a birth?",
    "Answer": "You must register your child\u2019s birth within 42 days at your local registry office.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "85cae754-8aa4-5ffc-8f1c-6eb00eef6d64"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "Can I get help with travel costs for medical appointments?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for help with travel costs through the NHS or your local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f7d6d4d7-5fec-5fe0-8a42-2df25baf04e3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is the Disabled Students\u2019 Allowance?",
    "Answer": "The Disabled Students\u2019 Allowance helps with extra costs for students with a disability.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f4a3786a-d05d-5004-b297-bcd08b107996"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Personal Independence Payment?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for PIP by filling out a form on the GOV.UK website or by phone.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a4d0dcb6-d54d-5603-997a-0c19dfd6c873"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "Can I get help with housing if I\u2019m disabled?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Disabled Facilities Grant to adapt your home to your needs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "b71b5ef5-f71a-5385-9aa9-57d6526268eb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is the Disability Living Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Disability Living Allowance provides financial support for children with disabilities.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f047da41-9daa-5a5e-bf7b-ce637f42c267"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Carer\u2019s Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Carer\u2019s Allowance online or by phone through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "16fe5d37-0678-54cf-b968-74a300e0dbca"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is Carer's Credit?",
    "Answer": "Carer\u2019s Credit helps carers fill gaps in their National Insurance record protecting their State Pension.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "26c18f99-88c6-58f5-8b48-d7e42fc43ab4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I get financial support for being a carer?",
    "Answer": "Yes Carer\u2019s Allowance is the main benefit for carers with additional support available through other benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "60d6e34c-d885-5e8e-9746-b1fc703ee1a8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I get help with respite care?",
    "Answer": "Respite care is provided by local councils and care agencies to give carers a break.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "547d1db6-09d8-5351-9d42-989b19309c59"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is the Carer\u2019s Allowance earnings limit?",
    "Answer": "You must earn less than a specified amount to qualify for Carer\u2019s Allowance.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5a9ac9ab-6029-5b76-bd19-9974c75656a5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Housing Benefit?",
    "Answer": "Housing Benefit helps pay your rent if you\u2019re on a low income and you can apply through your local council.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1a349562-ffb1-54b0-9763-8d21dda6f231"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is Pension Credit?",
    "Answer": "Pension Credit is an income-related benefit for people over State Pension age.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "b025b26b-f043-57f3-bb9c-cf0e5a94b9da"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "Can I get help with utility bills?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for schemes like the Warm Home Discount or the Winter Fuel Payment.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1f45ce9e-1458-5343-9b3a-791123f0d2ed"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Social Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Social Fund provides financial support for people in urgent need like after a disaster or in a crisis.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "7b638639-6f1d-5507-a8ff-a2e590cf130a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for a Budgeting Advance?",
    "Answer": "Apply for a Budgeting Advance if you\u2019re on Universal Credit and need help with emergency costs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ad6c1637-dc66-5333-b447-02900a6348e2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What happens to benefits when someone dies?",
    "Answer": "Most benefits stop after the death of the recipient but some may be transferred or adjusted.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f18f9aeb-dd59-5a0b-acd4-01f46e9ea6c3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I get help with inheritance tax?",
    "Answer": "There are government schemes and advice available to help with inheritance tax if you qualify.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a4850ad5-89c8-5bd6-a2f7-5eaba10234dc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Bereavement Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Bereavement Allowance through the GOV.UK website or by phone.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "c80931e6-1118-557e-bce9-7bc2d7a3f017"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is the Death Grant?",
    "Answer": "The Death Grant was a payment made to help with funeral costs but it has been replaced by other schemes.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5311f02b-3ddf-5d75-84f0-38f667f4067f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I transfer my partner\u2019s State Pension?",
    "Answer": "In some cases you may inherit part of your partner\u2019s State Pension after their death.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f9aa78e3-277c-5f64-bd0b-020564cb3499"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I report fraud or misuse of benefits?",
    "Answer": "You can report suspected fraud online or by phone through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "70e21814-d148-5123-9788-298ea18b436d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What happens if my benefit application is rejected?",
    "Answer": "If your application is rejected you can request a mandatory reconsideration or appeal the decision.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "dd454eb0-08c1-535f-97b0-250a0dcf1162"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I update my bank details for benefit payments?",
    "Answer": "Update your bank details through your online benefits account or by contacting your benefit office.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "96066372-a1c4-5576-9c67-5203a4690f1e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "Can I receive benefits if I\u2019m working?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for certain benefits even if you\u2019re working depending on your income and circumstances.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2c2bcc32-e587-56a9-9e2f-03fcba137c16"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What is a benefit cap?",
    "Answer": "A benefit cap is a limit on the total amount of benefits that most people aged 16 to 64 can receive.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "54d902db-c0dd-50c8-8716-f1f7ed18cf36"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the Flexible Support Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Flexible Support Fund helps job seekers with the costs associated with finding work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "0c49d6e7-1d44-5971-90a9-5987cfbc4ae2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "Can I receive training while on Jobseeker\u2019s Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Yes training opportunities are available and some may be funded through your benefits.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "cc20458d-88a0-5dc1-85d8-2e963c0b93c2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I apply for the New Enterprise Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Apply through your Jobcentre Plus work coach who will assess your business idea.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6fefc0a2-9c06-570b-bdbd-680a9b645cc4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is a work trial?",
    "Answer": "A work trial is a short-term placement with an employer where you can demonstrate your skills.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "9f97eb24-a984-5367-8c41-9cb3be904e51"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What should I do if I lose my job?",
    "Answer": "You should apply for Jobseeker\u2019s Allowance or Universal Credit and look for new job opportunities.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2ed63603-9b4c-5a22-843c-7e153dede85e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I claim ESA if I have a temporary disability?",
    "Answer": "Yes you may be eligible for ESA if you have a temporary condition that affects your ability to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "3f95da69-6c3b-51a9-a11f-2e01d11c4ad9"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is an ESA50 form?",
    "Answer": "An ESA50 form is used to assess how your illness or disability affects your ability to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "08fd644c-cc15-5245-85c6-2ffc939bbc31"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I notify the government if I\u2019m able to return to work?",
    "Answer": "Notify your benefits office or Jobcentre Plus as soon as you are able to return to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "729f44a6-253e-5214-835f-e0083fc3e1dd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I apply for ESA while on SSP?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for ESA when your Statutory Sick Pay ends if you\u2019re still unable to work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "33d0fca6-fff6-52da-87f4-bd7d4e898351"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is the maximum duration for claiming SSP?",
    "Answer": "You can claim Statutory Sick Pay for up to 28 weeks.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "d8c8bded-846c-550a-a8b6-0be5689564d5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Child Maintenance Service?",
    "Answer": "The Child Maintenance Service helps separated parents provide financial support for their children.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "b527fddb-9651-5f35-a842-7b91c362e1a2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Shared Parental Leave?",
    "Answer": "You must notify your employer at least eight weeks before you intend to take Shared Parental Leave.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "32b06c2f-d4d0-5a20-88ba-b73eff1b3e44"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is Tax-Free Childcare?",
    "Answer": "Tax-Free Childcare helps working parents with the cost of childcare.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1e13f5fc-ad2a-5daa-97e3-6e3270e6c340"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "Can I get financial help for adopting a child?",
    "Answer": "Yes you may be eligible for Adoption Allowance and other financial support.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "98270ecd-9707-5414-9879-0b1dcd95b2d3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is the Childcare Choices program?",
    "Answer": "Childcare Choices is a government initiative that offers financial support for childcare.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a462d720-ef93-51e6-8626-68b47ab860b1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I apply for the Access to Work scheme?",
    "Answer": "Apply online or through your Jobcentre Plus work coach to receive support in the workplace.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "198aead1-39e0-5427-8bf2-3d50b5586cdf"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Severe Disability Premium?",
    "Answer": "Severe Disability Premium is an extra amount paid on top of other benefits if you qualify.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "00c7efdc-7ed9-512e-94ea-2b04f79e656b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "Can I get help with home adaptations?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Disabled Facilities Grant to help adapt your home.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "78db2fce-32c5-565f-b8fd-12d09f098d91"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Industrial Injuries Disablement Benefit?",
    "Answer": "This benefit provides financial support if you\u2019re disabled due to an accident at work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "d0c9f40a-d7f9-5654-a6cc-b87d802c71de"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I claim disability premiums?",
    "Answer": "Disability premiums are automatically added to certain benefits if you qualify.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1d15cf86-d013-58bc-9d1a-0ab211a44464"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is Direct Payment for carers?",
    "Answer": "Direct Payments allow carers to receive funds directly to arrange care services.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "7ec4fd5d-e8b9-5aad-8fb5-1d7518491065"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I receive Carer's Allowance if I\u2019m over State Pension age?",
    "Answer": "You can receive Carer\u2019s Allowance if you\u2019re over State Pension age but it may affect your pension.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "29755787-71f6-55ee-83f4-c628a06c826f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I get a break from caring?",
    "Answer": "Respite care services can provide short-term relief for carers.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ba7fcb90-2a7d-5fa3-bbd1-b952023c4251"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What support groups are available for carers?",
    "Answer": "There are numerous local and national support groups for carers that offer advice and community.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "097ece5d-487b-5462-b23c-47243c4d5c74"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is the Carer\u2019s Allowance earnings limit?",
    "Answer": "You must earn less than a certain amount each week to qualify for Carer\u2019s Allowance.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5a9ac9ab-6029-5b76-bd19-9974c75656a5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Jobcentre Plus Travel Discount Card?",
    "Answer": "This card offers discounted travel for job seekers to attend interviews and work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "11d5b25d-8c48-5595-bafd-05659c1a2154"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "Can I get help with school uniforms?",
    "Answer": "Some local councils offer grants or vouchers to help with the cost of school uniforms.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "014d43d1-c6f6-5ed9-a2da-e3d7f3f0800d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Winter Fuel Payment?",
    "Answer": "The Winter Fuel Payment helps with heating costs during the winter months.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "33b01b49-9b71-5340-b195-6d5effff6e52"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Child Tax Credit?",
    "Answer": "Child Tax Credit helps with the costs of raising children and can be applied for through HMRC.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f9b1c720-f8a9-591c-8e93-15ea79332310"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Discretionary Assistance Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Discretionary Assistance Fund provides emergency financial help in Wales.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6d55b4cb-86aa-55a3-89b2-044473d8427f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I cancel a State Pension after a death?",
    "Answer": "Contact the Pension Service to cancel a State Pension after someone dies.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4d5ef06f-b7d0-5a94-8357-474fab5b8ad8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What happens to joint benefits when one person dies?",
    "Answer": "Joint benefits may be transferred or adjusted depending on the circumstances.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6734780b-ed0e-59ae-acf9-b1bc19d7e4a2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I inherit my spouse\u2019s private pension?",
    "Answer": "In some cases you may inherit part or all of your spouse\u2019s private pension.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "05dfc4bf-0f96-5bf1-bc95-31d2c5ea097d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is Probate?",
    "Answer": "Probate is the legal process of dealing with someone\u2019s estate after they die.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "d478f908-2a95-529a-982c-c4b4dfd03591"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I notify the bank of a death?",
    "Answer": "You should notify the deceased\u2019s bank as soon as possible providing a death certificate and other necessary documents.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5f11e7b1-4c4a-5ee1-83b0-160786e82250"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I report a change in my circumstances?",
    "Answer": "You can report changes in your circumstances through your online benefits account or by contacting your benefit office.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "df89445f-937d-56ec-a66c-48914a129898"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "Can I backdate my benefit claim?",
    "Answer": "In some cases benefits can be backdated if you have a valid reason for the delay in your application.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "c4b7433d-38c9-5e18-b725-eac7f3279c56"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "What should I do if I receive a benefits overpayment?",
    "Answer": "Contact your benefits office immediately to arrange repayment or discuss your options.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "800fa936-0860-5d93-bd95-ac2a1bb90d5a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "How do I challenge a benefits decision?",
    "Answer": "You can request a mandatory reconsideration or appeal to challenge a benefits decision.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "75231d13-1017-5f18-8c21-4e65a35625e2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Manage existing benefit",
    "Question": "Can I receive more than one benefit?",
    "Answer": "Yes you may be eligible for multiple benefits depending on your circumstances.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ce662df2-80ed-549f-be32-a02e8de2242f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the Restart Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Restart Scheme offers tailored support to help long-term unemployed people find work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f2ca3157-5266-5223-8243-1cdb35338e01"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "Can I work part-time while on Jobseeker\u2019s Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Yes but your allowance may be reduced based on your earnings.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "00aa8e72-b536-51b9-a540-e4f62d24acc0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is a work coach?",
    "Answer": "A work coach is assigned to you by Jobcentre Plus to help you find and stay in work.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2b11df04-d947-5fe7-bad0-7fdd3fa187dd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "How do I apply for income support?",
    "Answer": "You can apply for income support through the GOV.UK website if you meet the eligibility criteria.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2ce2137a-dd13-55cb-b47d-71f043b2f983"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Looking for work",
    "Question": "What is the Kickstart Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Kickstart Scheme provides funding to employers to create jobs for young people.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "b43e7c42-8e15-50d1-be68-f6be9cd71900"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is New Style ESA?",
    "Answer": "New Style ESA is a contributory benefit for those who have paid enough National Insurance contributions.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "11126854-7284-599f-8ca3-a3ef1548af70"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "Can I receive ESA while receiving other benefits?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can receive ESA along with certain other benefits but it may affect the amount you get.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "2344ac1d-36ce-521b-a856-cbc4e8e3ee31"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What happens if I\u2019m still sick after SSP ends?",
    "Answer": "You may be able to claim ESA or another benefit if you\u2019re still unable to work after your SSP ends.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "65c4c178-022d-505b-82af-2794fe166d32"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "How do I appeal an ESA decision?",
    "Answer": "You can appeal an ESA decision by requesting a mandatory reconsideration and if necessary appeal to a tribunal.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "311df17d-0b09-5a16-ab36-b693fbfe7d96"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Temporarily unable to work",
    "Question": "What is permitted work while on ESA?",
    "Answer": "Permitted work allows you to work a limited number of hours and earn a certain amount while still receiving ESA.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "b9e21dcf-cb04-521d-a997-5a9349f563c8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is Child Benefit?",
    "Answer": "Child Benefit is a payment made to parents or guardians to help with the cost of raising children.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "a73838c4-bbae-5b3c-ab97-a00f56e0eeb0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Maternity Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Maternity Allowance is for those who don\u2019t qualify for Statutory Maternity Pay and can be applied for through the GOV.UK website.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "45b9a57a-b819-54a7-860a-e05af62c6f9e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "Can I get financial help with school trips?",
    "Answer": "Some schools and local councils offer financial help with school trips for low-income families.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1af4fc1a-b659-5191-8619-805459e607f5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "What is Shared Parental Pay?",
    "Answer": "Shared Parental Pay allows parents to share time off work after the birth or adoption of a child.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f93f1c47-e570-5e9e-b8d8-642576d26fbf"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Families",
    "Question": "How do I apply for a Child Trust Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Child Trust Fund was a savings scheme for children and while it\u2019s no longer available you can manage existing accounts online.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f169d134-cb7b-5b3f-8aa8-ea7adff65083"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is the Disabled Facilities Grant?",
    "Answer": "The Disabled Facilities Grant helps with the cost of home adaptations for disabled people.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ed126a4a-871b-5678-b051-0ab305c17186"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "Can I get help with mobility aids?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for financial support to purchase mobility aids through various schemes.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "12ae4d77-2d82-5a98-a0df-917fa2b434cd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is the Blue Badge Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Blue Badge Scheme allows disabled people to park closer to their destination.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "ffa99307-c523-5e2d-bb6a-8e9f24ba96b7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Attendance Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Attendance Allowance is for people over State Pension age who need help with personal care and can be applied for online.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "64a1c2de-2744-560b-9c08-3108ddf00912"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Disabled or health condition",
    "Question": "What is Severe Disablement Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Severe Disablement Allowance was a benefit for those unable to work due to illness or disability it\u2019s now replaced by ESA for new claims.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "5c0c0d4f-0397-5747-b87f-e95f3c96b758"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is Carer\u2019s Support Allowance?",
    "Answer": "Carer\u2019s Support Allowance is financial support for those who care for someone with a disability or illness.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "0c317ee7-33fc-5aee-ab7c-20396ea9eee3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Carer\u2019s Credit?",
    "Answer": "Carer\u2019s Credit helps fill gaps in your National Insurance record and can be applied for online.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "066f4aef-2719-5c0e-81ae-c18b8cb6068d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "What is the difference between Carer\u2019s Allowance and Carer\u2019s Credit?",
    "Answer": "Carer\u2019s Allowance provides financial support while Carer\u2019s Credit protects your State Pension by filling gaps in your National Insurance record.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "8e21f28f-0159-5704-89a1-cc2001c3d6ae"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "Can I receive Carer\u2019s Allowance if I\u2019m retired?",
    "Answer": "You can receive Carer\u2019s Allowance if you meet the criteria but it may affect your pension.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f1de2fe2-04f6-5864-8f00-3fb6df0308f5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Caring for someone",
    "Question": "How do I get help with the emotional stress of caring?",
    "Answer": "There are support groups counseling services and helplines available for carers dealing with emotional stress.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "cc67078e-1682-5da8-b6b9-38127126d35f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Help to Save scheme?",
    "Answer": "Help to Save is a government savings account for people on low incomes offering bonuses on your savings.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "6667025f-30f1-5414-87d3-f4580ba9eec3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "Can I get help with rent arrears?",
    "Answer": "If you\u2019re struggling with rent arrears you may be eligible for a Discretionary Housing Payment or other support.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "9f48ac4f-a2be-5a27-abca-039b9baeabeb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Local Welfare Assistance scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Local Welfare Assistance scheme provides emergency financial help often for things like food clothing and utilities.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "716932b0-0108-53dd-aaf3-e6987edf49d0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Working Tax Credit?",
    "Answer": "Working Tax Credit supports people on low incomes who are in work and you can apply through HMRC.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "7a0806d0-1ee2-53b9-b2f0-a94cfd9099e3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Low income",
    "Question": "What is the Hardship Fund?",
    "Answer": "The Hardship Fund provides financial assistance to those in urgent need often administered by local councils.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1de51675-1a98-5ea3-b6f6-bcb97cecf08b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is a Coroner\u2019s inquest?",
    "Answer": "A Coroner\u2019s inquest is an investigation into a death that was sudden unexplained or suspicious.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "1acbb552-3bab-5354-bc99-6f80837eaccb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "Can I claim bereavement benefits if I wasn\u2019t married?",
    "Answer": "In some cases cohabiting partners may be eligible for bereavement benefits depending on the circumstances.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "9f539deb-9627-54d5-abf2-5686a0d8a7d2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I apply for Bereavement Support Payment?",
    "Answer": "Apply for Bereavement Support Payment through the GOV.UK website or by phone.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "4af95fc6-0b40-5894-9fb6-dd53b9136cab"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "What is the Tell Us Once service?",
    "Answer": "The Tell Us Once service allows you to report a death to most government organizations in one go.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "f359e5f5-b3a2-5216-bc93-5238798a59cb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "When someone dies",
    "Question": "How do I arrange a funeral if I can\u2019t afford it?",
    "Answer": "You may be eligible for a Funeral Expenses Payment if you\u2019re on a low income and can\u2019t afford the funeral costs.",
    "Section": "general claim benefits",
    "id": "347d094a-05a4-5fe8-93cb-a75c673d0b09"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Who is eligible to file a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Any patient or their family member who has suffered harm due to substandard care can file a medical negligence claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c3c80f19-54ab-5c39-83cd-a2d3b08110ab"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What must be proven to establish a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "To establish a medical negligence claim you must prove that the care provided was below the standard expected and directly caused harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5d59b4dc-5147-5211-a03b-bd81f55f63a2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can family members claim for the death of a loved one due to medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Yes family members can claim compensation if a loved one dies due to negligent medical care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ebce3c3b-fc0f-5e39-b35f-9d1d0e2b683d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Who can make a claim on behalf of a child in a medical negligence case?",
    "Answer": "A parent or legal guardian can file a claim on behalf of a child who has been harmed by medical negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d892e159-c948-5bcb-8610-b48c8b464119"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Is it possible to claim for psychiatric harm caused by medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can claim for psychiatric harm if it resulted from negligent medical treatment.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "eeeef673-5f24-5aca-9970-653a64dd6c48"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What is the time limit to file a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Generally the time limit to file a medical negligence claim is three years from the date of injury or from the date the harm was discovered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2a6be4e1-999e-5969-b33b-ae6368d384fa"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Who can claim compensation for a birth injury?",
    "Answer": "Parents or guardians can claim compensation on behalf of a child who has suffered a birth injury due to medical negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "955c53ff-13e6-5316-b07d-5140afcc0170"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can a patient claim if they were harmed by a delayed diagnosis?",
    "Answer": "Yes patients can claim compensation if a delayed diagnosis caused harm due to substandard medical care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "da6729eb-ebdf-5869-bc6e-74116b5017a2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Are there any exceptions to the three-year time limit for filing claims?",
    "Answer": "Exceptions can be made if the claimant was a minor at the time of the injury or if the injury was not discovered immediately.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7dcb6a87-b59d-575e-940a-b0500a6a0750"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What are the specific conditions for claiming on behalf of a deceased patient?",
    "Answer": "Claims on behalf of a deceased patient can be made if it can be proven that their death resulted from negligent medical care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3daffcee-89e7-5364-b389-1dd5017768af"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What does \"duty of care\" mean in medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Duty of care refers to the legal obligation of healthcare providers to offer a standard level of care to their patients.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bcdf2353-4964-5afc-9773-e0c1597d41ba"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How is a breach of duty of care determined in a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "A breach of duty is determined if it can be shown that the care provided was below the standard expected of a competent professional.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "38ad12ba-c6e8-5201-9391-3ef45d40487a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can a claim be made if the duty of care was not breached but the patient still suffered harm?",
    "Answer": "No for a successful claim it must be proven that the harm was a direct result of a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b83b1174-5cfc-5e99-b545-8fa89c098f16"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What is considered a breach of duty of care in surgical procedures?",
    "Answer": "A breach occurs when a surgeon fails to perform an operation to the accepted medical standards leading to patient harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9b3d3b31-8a01-596a-a8b5-588d59debf51"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How does the duty of care apply to mental health care providers?",
    "Answer": "Mental health care providers must offer care that meets the professional standards and a breach occurs if substandard care causes harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d33d262a-6450-5788-9c8c-84c39d2fa981"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What role does informed consent play in the duty of care?",
    "Answer": "Informed consent is crucial; failing to obtain it can be considered a breach of duty if the patient suffers as a result.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "be4518c3-51e8-59ae-8839-270bc2f4cd68"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Is misdiagnosis always considered a breach of duty of care?",
    "Answer": "Not always; a misdiagnosis is a breach only if it was due to negligence or failure to follow standard diagnostic procedures.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7a126f7a-288e-5880-8b5e-5288449a7843"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How does failure to diagnose impact duty of care claims?",
    "Answer": "Failure to diagnose can be considered a breach if it leads to harm that could have been prevented with timely intervention.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bd431828-f303-59c8-b871-fc6b98f2c50e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What is the significance of clinical guidelines in determining a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Clinical guidelines help establish the standard of care expected; deviation from these can indicate a breach of duty.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "338e5a31-11f3-5094-b631-c9d4c26a0338"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can poor communication between healthcare providers be a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Yes poor communication that results in harm to the patient can be considered a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9e9783ea-51ce-5b86-9d9f-3e951f765bf2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What is causation in the context of medical negligence claims?",
    "Answer": "Causation refers to the need to prove that the harm suffered by the patient was directly caused by the negligent care provided.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bb959844-10ad-5b40-8c7b-2937458a182f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How do you prove causation in a medical negligence case?",
    "Answer": "Causation is proven by showing a direct link between the healthcare provider's breach of duty and the harm caused to the patient.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b7cd20df-fa7c-59af-94f4-6c8454b76f60"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Is it difficult to establish causation in medical negligence claims?",
    "Answer": "Establishing causation can be challenging especially in complex cases where multiple factors may have contributed to the harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "db0c4cb0-af65-510b-95fa-77eb8b096b47"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be established if the harm was only partially due to negligence?",
    "Answer": "Yes causation can still be established if negligence was a significant contributing factor to the harm even if not the sole cause.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "03b12538-fe8b-5ba1-8c5e-b77cb74518de"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What evidence is needed to establish causation in a negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Medical records expert testimony and other documentation that shows a direct link between the breach of duty and the harm caused are needed.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ce87340a-cd15-5713-bd14-1bf911ffa6a9"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How does the \"but for\" test apply to proving causation?",
    "Answer": "The \"but for\" test is used to determine if the harm would not have occurred \"but for\" the negligent action or omission.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7cf1004b-3887-5639-80cc-fc683c3ef592"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What role do expert witnesses play in establishing causation?",
    "Answer": "Expert witnesses provide testimony to establish whether the harm resulted from the breach of duty and how it could have been avoided.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1917c407-98f2-50e9-a995-0bacf71098cd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be disproven if the patient had a pre-existing condition?",
    "Answer": "Causation can be complex in such cases but it must be shown that negligence significantly worsened the patient\u2019s condition.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "01ec01fd-4026-501c-ae29-9845a4503a2c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How is causation addressed in cases involving delayed treatment?",
    "Answer": "Causation must show that the delay directly resulted in harm that would have been avoided with timely treatment.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "71e94404-393d-5fbf-bded-42da403e2c20"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What is the \"material contribution\" test in medical negligence claims?",
    "Answer": "The material contribution test assesses whether the negligent action materially contributed to the harm even if it was not the sole cause.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8a429326-f719-569b-9901-3f62b1f161ad"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What is the limitation period for filing a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period is typically three years from the date of injury or the date when the injury was discovered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8683f282-165b-50e5-8cae-01fa3bee7cc5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Are there any exceptions to the three-year limitation period?",
    "Answer": "Yes exceptions include cases involving children or individuals who were mentally incapacitated at the time of the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1537eb8f-85e6-5560-ae2f-63df3332d6d4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can a claim be filed after the three-year limitation period has expired?",
    "Answer": "In some cases the court may allow a claim to proceed if there were valid reasons for the delay but this is not guaranteed.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "48358c20-b596-5a9a-b12d-c595b45c4ed2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What happens if the limitation period is missed?",
    "Answer": "If the limitation period is missed the claim may be time-barred and you may lose the right to seek compensation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5fbb71ba-e92f-53bf-a7ce-05a75034648b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Does the limitation period apply to claims involving minors?",
    "Answer": "No the three-year limitation period typically starts when the minor reaches the age of 18.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "fb5fe512-cd45-5d20-9910-02961499ee15"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period work for claims involving deceased patients?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period generally begins from the date of death or from when the cause of death was discovered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1304ab8f-0778-5b90-b971-a85b388372e8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can the limitation period be extended in cases of late diagnosis?",
    "Answer": "Yes the limitation period may be extended if the injury or harm was not discovered until later.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8822c043-0686-5f16-b508-eed8bce5a681"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What is the limitation period for claims involving mental health issues?",
    "Answer": "For individuals lacking mental capacity the limitation period does not begin until they regain capacity or a guardian is appointed.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d74e8588-cde0-5ad6-b488-2295a02d922d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period apply to continuing treatment?",
    "Answer": "If harm occurs over a period of continuing treatment the limitation period may start from the end of that treatment.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5c44cbbd-a31a-538d-9bdd-b55f103928b8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What steps should be taken if you're close to the end of the limitation period?",
    "Answer": "If you are nearing the end of the limitation period it's crucial to seek legal advice immediately to avoid losing your right to claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2eff8e22-a2e5-5131-915c-8751ca7065cf"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What are general damages in a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "General damages compensate for non-financial losses such as pain suffering and loss of amenity.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8ce31747-5dd6-50c0-b596-726483d0a7f0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What are special damages in a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Special damages cover financial losses and expenses incurred due to the injury such as medical bills and lost income.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2b6ad3e9-a7ec-5512-aed2-933211062a2b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How are general and special damages different?",
    "Answer": "General damages cover non-economic losses while special damages compensate for specific financial expenses related to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7bb9b460-5504-54d9-8204-641d73ebac81"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can you claim both general and special damages in a medical negligence case?",
    "Answer": "Yes a successful claim can include both general and special damages to cover all aspects of the harm suffered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "01700188-681a-5059-b6bc-ae54af446369"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What factors influence the amount of general damages awarded?",
    "Answer": "The severity of the injury the impact on quality of life and the duration of pain and suffering influence the amount awarded.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3ef70113-b7fd-5c24-9ed8-aab577acc359"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How are special damages calculated?",
    "Answer": "Special damages are calculated based on actual financial losses such as medical costs travel expenses and lost earnings.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "f4e8954f-e3cc-5abf-91a8-dedcae660414"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can future losses be included in special damages?",
    "Answer": "Yes special damages can include compensation for future medical care and loss of future earnings due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c3f8a351-bc44-5736-8a63-f45a8221ab55"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What is the role of expert testimony in determining damages?",
    "Answer": "Experts provide assessments on the extent of the injury and the impact on the patient\u2019s life which helps determine the amount of damages.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b7c8532c-9cf5-51cd-88f8-d0b28ea26ec7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How do courts assess claims for loss of earnings?",
    "Answer": "Courts consider the patient\u2019s salary potential career progression and the duration of time they are unable to work.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "eb278329-a7af-5d6c-b43b-dd74bcb3df50"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Are there caps on the amount of damages that can be awarded?",
    "Answer": "In the UK there is no fixed cap on damages but awards are guided by previous case law and judicial guidelines.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "75a2c826-54fe-5fdc-aea9-3defdd9a7266"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What is the process for reporting a medical negligence claim to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Claims affecting benefits should be reported to the DWP with full documentation detailing the injury and its impact on entitlements.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e6a680e0-0926-5623-9462-b7d90f15a0da"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Why must claims be reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Reporting to the DWP is necessary if the injury affects benefits or if compensation might influence benefit entitlements.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5af6b17f-89f9-5871-9917-a512654ee612"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How does compensation impact benefits reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Compensation may reduce the amount of benefits received and this must be reported to ensure accurate benefit adjustments.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "40dd06f6-cd39-5983-a9a8-e78cb571ecac"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What documentation is needed to report a claim to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "You need to provide medical records details of the injury and the outcome of the claim when reporting to the DWP.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "08c6610c-6466-5df3-9deb-561fa7021f7a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Can the DWP recover benefits from a compensation award?",
    "Answer": "Yes the DWP may recover benefits paid to you if the compensation includes amounts for losses that benefits were intended to cover.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3589ca44-c0f5-5cd7-b8a4-6c28edd75c14"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How does the DWP handle overpayments in relation to compensation claims?",
    "Answer": "If overpayments were made due to a delay in reporting the DWP may seek to recover those amounts from the compensation awarded.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "40d6c5e2-86a3-5f99-aff4-74e40a7f617c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What is the role of the Compensation Recovery Unit in DWP reporting?",
    "Answer": "The Compensation Recovery Unit (CRU) ensures that benefits are correctly adjusted following a compensation award.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "89113fa5-5f5a-5b08-8b45-a04a0fba59c1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "When should a medical negligence claim be reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "A claim should be reported as soon as it becomes clear that the injury might impact benefit entitlements.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2929af8a-d0a1-51c6-9a23-b05c8210a27a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What happens if a claim is not reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Failure to report can result in overpayment of benefits which the DWP may later seek to recover from the compensation awarded.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c6913c7f-50ca-5813-aebd-b1218e611ddf"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Can legal advice help with DWP reporting in a negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Yes legal advice can ensure that all necessary information is accurately reported to the DWP to avoid complications.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d2aa2eb5-eccd-5552-987a-d372c1b46c95"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What is the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The Early Notification Scheme is designed to promote early reporting and resolution of severe birth-related brain injuries.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "13e4a600-4c6b-5550-b33b-4bb34c3a83ae"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Who is covered by the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The scheme covers cases of severe brain injury occurring during birth which are reported within a specified timeframe.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1edab874-d302-5e5b-b41a-5089d8066e96"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme benefit families?",
    "Answer": "It helps families by providing early investigation and potential resolution of claims reducing the time and stress involved.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b65ca390-75cc-521c-b86b-3f1d23ee6c2d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What types of injuries are addressed by the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "The scheme focuses on severe brain injuries sustained during birth particularly those related to oxygen deprivation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5a7c826f-b34b-5da6-a418-bc19746a36c4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Is participation in the Early Notification Scheme mandatory?",
    "Answer": "Yes hospitals are required to report qualifying cases of severe brain injury to the scheme within a specific timeframe.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1ae52255-44e5-5c4e-8802-7316f1490706"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme expedite the claims process?",
    "Answer": "The scheme aims to resolve claims more quickly by initiating early investigations and encouraging early settlement discussions.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7a460b55-cb8d-5f9a-88e5-0443aedc1f2e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What is the role of healthcare providers in the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "Healthcare providers must report qualifying injuries and cooperate with investigations to facilitate early resolution of claims.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "0bbf0c47-83bc-5278-9da0-b854ebb7db81"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Can claims outside of birth-related brain injuries use the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "No the scheme is specifically focused on severe brain injuries occurring during birth and does not apply to other types of injuries.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "46e96ac2-ca60-5659-b3c2-e9e11dd403ec"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme affect compensation awards?",
    "Answer": "The scheme encourages early settlements which can lead to quicker compensation payments without lengthy legal processes.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b6463d05-954f-5262-b384-e5be75d1f50c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What happens if a qualifying injury is not reported under the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "Failure to report can lead to delays in claim resolution and may affect the ability to settle the claim early.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "90601d69-e4ee-55bc-8682-41216288467f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What are vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "Vaginal mesh claims involve seeking compensation for complications caused by vaginal mesh implants such as pain or erosion.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "fcdb0eee-43fd-5eb9-b6ab-96680befb63f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Who can file a vaginal mesh claim?",
    "Answer": "Women who have suffered complications from vaginal mesh implants such as pain infection or organ damage can file a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bc6dfd94-211c-5771-9996-ea491b3107e4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What are the common complications associated with vaginal mesh implants?",
    "Answer": "Common complications include chronic pain infection erosion of the mesh into surrounding tissues and difficulty in removal.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ae202aa2-cd0f-5765-b892-b9c1a789afff"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "How is liability established in vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "Liability is established by proving that the implant was defective or that the procedure was performed negligently leading to harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bc96b77c-c041-57cd-8541-013072d3df84"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What compensation can be sought in vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "Compensation can cover medical expenses for corrective surgeries pain and suffering and any long-term impact on quality of life.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "f60dd357-c702-50fa-ba2d-f8e8d1bb2204"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What evidence is needed to support a vaginal mesh claim?",
    "Answer": "Medical records proof of the complications and expert testimony linking the mesh implant to the injuries are crucial for supporting a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9f79b47a-ece1-5310-8705-5aefa0583ec1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period apply to vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period typically starts from the date when the complications were discovered or should have been discovered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c7e8ee14-80aa-5b7d-9a83-7e61e5dffeac"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can vaginal mesh claims include future medical costs?",
    "Answer": "Yes claims can include compensation for future surgeries or ongoing medical care related to the complications caused by the mesh.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1131918c-b495-578a-ac33-331c9a1f5c45"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What are the legal precedents for vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "Legal precedents include successful claims where the courts have awarded compensation for pain suffering and corrective surgeries.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "09ba8afe-bf27-5a5e-8489-e56ec9c8a386"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Are there any specific regulations regarding vaginal mesh implants?",
    "Answer": "Yes there have been regulations and guidelines issued to ensure the safety of vaginal mesh implants and to reduce the risk of complications.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8675e658-0bac-557f-98f9-3a8bd54cda14"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What are sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Sodium valproate claims involve seeking compensation for birth defects or developmental disorders caused by the use of the drug during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "08311678-a4c5-5bf2-af59-d2c2d0acdc5d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Who is eligible to file a sodium valproate claim?",
    "Answer": "Parents of children born with birth defects or developmental disorders linked to the mother's use of sodium valproate during pregnancy can file a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c31bac73-a011-523a-99c1-c1f9a07e602f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What are the risks associated with sodium valproate during pregnancy?",
    "Answer": "Risks include a high likelihood of birth defects and developmental issues in children exposed to the drug in utero.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "eb611f54-343f-578c-87d3-5118a1aa5b9e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "How can causation be proven in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Causation can be proven by linking the use of sodium valproate during pregnancy to the child\u2019s birth defects or developmental issues.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ecbcfd9f-a4d8-5db4-89fd-74423919fd81"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What compensation is available in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Compensation can cover medical expenses special education needs and long-term care costs for the affected child.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c75031fa-e115-5ea1-b231-dec9e2febda2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What is the limitation period for filing a sodium valproate claim?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period generally starts from the date of diagnosis of the birth defect or developmental disorder.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2af2740e-9c81-522a-b70b-238586189a44"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "How have courts ruled in previous sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Courts have awarded compensation in cases where it was proven that the drug caused significant harm to the child.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "80273c33-80e7-586a-83be-d1001550fa30"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What should be included in a sodium valproate claim?",
    "Answer": "Claims should include medical records proof of the child\u2019s condition and evidence linking the condition to the drug\u2019s use during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "31c22462-d27b-5ed6-9e91-01b9bfcf10ec"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Can claims be made for sodium valproate prescribed without proper warnings?",
    "Answer": "Yes if it can be proven that the healthcare provider failed to warn of the risks associated with the drug during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c12d3115-4ef5-59ec-9f27-19f359dbe89a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What role do expert witnesses play in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Expert witnesses provide critical testimony linking the drug to the child\u2019s condition and assessing the long-term impact of the harm caused.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "6f08382d-6931-5ec6-8b90-136d7d2ab8fa"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I claim if the harm was caused by a medication error?",
    "Answer": "Yes patients who suffer harm due to medication errors such as incorrect dosage or wrong prescription can file a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "f3067d68-28fd-593b-a978-49b58d88337d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What is the role of an independent medical expert in a negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "An independent medical expert assesses the standard of care provided and whether it deviated from accepted medical practices.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3ae8f188-6fd8-5f4c-8edd-daf931aee44d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I claim if the harm was caused by an inexperienced doctor?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can claim if the harm resulted from negligence regardless of the doctor\u2019s experience level.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4a8bf89a-fdb5-55f4-a0a8-5e5c9147a278"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What should I do if I believe I have a medical negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Seek legal advice as soon as possible to assess the validity of your claim and understand the next steps.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4eb77d98-5040-5080-8a79-7d1f84576b03"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I claim for future complications caused by medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can claim compensation for future complications if they are likely to arise from the initial negligent treatment.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "be1d857d-86ad-57d5-80b3-df8391d96df6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Does a breach of duty of care include errors during surgery?",
    "Answer": "Yes surgical errors that result in harm can be considered a breach of duty of care if they occurred due to negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "de10540c-f214-5fab-a294-dc9ee2b39776"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How does the duty of care apply in emergency situations?",
    "Answer": "Even in emergencies healthcare providers must offer care that meets professional standards; failure to do so may constitute a breach.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "dd8873f9-e918-5906-b5fd-f8de0bd0daa2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Is failure to follow up on a patient\u2019s condition a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Yes if a healthcare provider fails to adequately monitor and follow up on a patient\u2019s condition it can be a breach of duty.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "954eda9a-15b9-5a55-8352-0dde76afb2b4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can poor record-keeping be a breach of duty of care?",
    "Answer": "Yes inadequate record-keeping that leads to patient harm can be considered a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "98ddbd0d-34b7-57b9-ad3e-7ead76df4c3c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What happens if a healthcare provider does not follow standard procedures?",
    "Answer": "Failing to follow standard procedures that result in patient harm is typically considered a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "f9c32b99-a53b-5d23-9786-e507f8e2e47a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be established if multiple factors contributed to the harm?",
    "Answer": "Yes causation can be established if the negligent act was a significant factor in causing the harm even if other factors were involved.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c3556590-7d02-5bd7-8be4-ca64bb135162"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How is causation proven in cases of delayed diagnosis?",
    "Answer": "Causation is proven by demonstrating that the delay in diagnosis directly led to a worsening of the patient\u2019s condition.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "12633be9-037a-515b-ab9f-719bdac3ee41"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be disproven if the harm was unavoidable?",
    "Answer": "Yes if it can be shown that the harm would have occurred regardless of the negligence causation may not be established.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "59ab00fd-2d81-5e25-948d-161d94bab069"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What is the significance of medical records in establishing causation?",
    "Answer": "Medical records provide crucial evidence that links the negligent act to the harm suffered supporting the claim of causation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ce2df3bb-cdc4-5eb0-a82e-6b3e23f99ae6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How does expert testimony support causation in complex cases?",
    "Answer": "Expert testimony helps clarify the connection between the breach of duty and the resulting harm especially in medically complex cases.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "cc43bb7a-c97c-598d-8ebb-7f6b7d127c02"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What is the limitation period for claims involving birth injuries?",
    "Answer": "For birth injuries the limitation period usually starts when the child turns 18 allowing them to claim up to the age of 21.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3b388104-3593-531d-a4d9-aad002fd5f7b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can the limitation period be extended in cases of gradual onset of symptoms?",
    "Answer": "Yes if symptoms develop gradually the limitation period may begin from the date the symptoms were first recognized as related to negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7a785425-f06d-5e92-85d5-a5922d92c06c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What steps can be taken if the limitation period is close to expiring?",
    "Answer": "You should file the claim as soon as possible or apply to the court for an extension if there are valid reasons for the delay.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "68a7b141-38ce-5d5c-898c-9e8acf671dca"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period affect claims for psychological harm?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period for psychological harm claims typically starts from the date the harm is diagnosed or recognized.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bbc54299-61b0-51e4-a42d-cc03ce10db96"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can a claim be filed if the patient was unaware of the harm within the limitation period?",
    "Answer": "Yes the limitation period can start from the date the patient became aware of the harm not necessarily when it occurred.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b2096d51-30c0-5d70-a2e4-68f38e84eba7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How do courts assess compensation for loss of consortium?",
    "Answer": "Courts assess the impact of the injury on the claimant\u2019s relationship with their partner when awarding compensation for loss of consortium.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9538179a-eaa5-5dbd-a3b1-9b3a43af2043"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can compensation cover the cost of private medical treatment?",
    "Answer": "Yes special damages can include the cost of private medical treatment if it is necessary due to the injury caused by negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c8d13503-0491-5f9a-b790-89ca026b851d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How is compensation calculated for loss of future earnings?",
    "Answer": "Compensation for loss of future earnings is based on the patient\u2019s age occupation and the impact of the injury on their ability to work.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "82f662bc-bf8a-5f47-bcd4-bf72f2771621"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can you claim for the cost of care provided by family members?",
    "Answer": "Yes the cost of care provided by family members can be claimed as special damages if it was necessary due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "86c356d8-c45f-5564-8779-d1f782f6bf8e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What role do rehabilitation costs play in special damages?",
    "Answer": "Rehabilitation costs including physiotherapy and occupational therapy are included in special damages if they are required due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c1aa26ca-913c-54d8-a04b-cf4c0b7d2b54"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What should be reported to the DWP if the claim affects disability benefits?",
    "Answer": "You should report the full details of the injury and the compensation awarded as it may affect the amount of disability benefits received.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "10eb355f-0025-5f96-a10d-8263d7ca7a43"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How does the DWP calculate benefit recovery from compensation awards?",
    "Answer": "The DWP calculates the recovery amount based on the overlap between the compensation and the benefits received for the same injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "a62afe0f-f2f5-5125-98cc-d95596d93646"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Can the DWP claim back benefits paid due to an injury?",
    "Answer": "Yes if compensation is awarded for the injury the DWP can recover the benefits paid during the period of injury-related incapacity.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "66b7b090-693d-5962-a7c2-16a49d7760c3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What happens if compensation is awarded for future losses?",
    "Answer": "If compensation includes amounts for future losses it may reduce or eliminate future benefit entitlements which must be reported to the DWP.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "daecca12-ecdb-5fb6-8346-479885c62e66"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What is the role of a solicitor in DWP reporting for negligence claims?",
    "Answer": "A solicitor ensures that all necessary information is accurately reported to the DWP and advises on the impact of the compensation on benefits.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e9e01e80-8622-5c9f-a69b-57a65a84a9bd"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme improve patient safety?",
    "Answer": "The scheme encourages early identification of issues which can lead to improvements in patient safety and prevent future harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3c6f69d9-028d-50c6-b37e-d1784cb61ffb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What happens if an injury is identified too late for the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "If an injury is identified after the reporting window it may not qualify for the scheme but can still be pursued as a standard negligence claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d33350a3-3842-5329-ad05-fce4a2140d86"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme differ from standard claims processes?",
    "Answer": "The scheme aims for quicker resolution and settlement often without the need for lengthy court proceedings.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "1899cc0c-2d18-5a87-956b-afd7aa4d08c2"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What support is available to families through the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "Families receive support through early communication access to medical records and potential early settlement of claims.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e3ad38b2-e143-5070-b692-9598870bc620"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Can the Early Notification Scheme be used for injuries outside of the birth context?",
    "Answer": "No the scheme is specifically designed for severe brain injuries that occur during birth and does not apply to other types of injuries.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b0bd31a7-8644-54ee-a10d-cd1ba781ecf0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "How has the use of vaginal mesh been regulated following complications?",
    "Answer": "Regulations have tightened and the use of vaginal mesh is now restricted with patients required to receive full information about risks.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3258c34a-b685-56e1-8d36-07eebae12990"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What are the alternatives to vaginal mesh for treating pelvic organ prolapse?",
    "Answer": "Alternatives include physiotherapy pessaries and non-mesh surgical options that do not carry the same risks as vaginal mesh implants.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c3b9e3a4-cb3e-5575-83ae-578e80a233ce"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can a claim be made if the vaginal mesh was implanted years ago?",
    "Answer": "Yes claims can still be made as long as they are within the limitation period starting from when the complications were discovered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7e4ef77b-a00c-58ab-bd3f-5345b5bd0fb6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What is the process for removing a vaginal mesh implant?",
    "Answer": "Removal is complex and may require multiple surgeries especially if the mesh has eroded into surrounding tissues.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "fd5a0ca7-f9e5-56a7-80a9-6fac957f47b4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can you claim for emotional distress caused by vaginal mesh complications?",
    "Answer": "Yes compensation for emotional distress can be included if it resulted from complications related to vaginal mesh implants.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d408708e-ff26-59ef-9817-af7b42fc2700"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What legal precedents exist for sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Several legal precedents have resulted in compensation awards for children affected by sodium valproate focusing on failure to warn of risks.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d5ab927c-6f92-5218-9124-02adb3d7b8b5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What information should have been provided to patients about sodium valproate?",
    "Answer": "Patients should have been informed about the significant risks of birth defects and developmental disorders associated with the drug.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "33b8d784-9d34-5f2f-8a01-168daf84ce4a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "How does the court determine compensation in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Compensation is based on the severity of the child\u2019s condition the impact on quality of life and the cost of ongoing care and support.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e1a24b61-068f-5863-b4a3-e7fddbe629d1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Can claims be made for developmental disorders linked to sodium valproate?",
    "Answer": "Yes claims can be made for developmental disorders if it can be proven they were caused by exposure to sodium valproate during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "6024af33-f17b-5ac9-a223-97ca15adfbb1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What role do healthcare providers play in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Healthcare providers may be liable if they failed to warn patients about the risks of using sodium valproate during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ad5cb0a4-17a3-5f23-9c9a-1f025b615bdf"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I make a claim if I received incorrect test results?",
    "Answer": "Yes if incorrect test results led to harm or delayed treatment you may be eligible to make a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7a5524e2-053e-5581-a553-0fe111d26a87"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Is it possible to claim for negligence if I consented to the procedure?",
    "Answer": "Yes but only if it can be shown that the harm was caused by negligence and not a known risk that you were informed about.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2875c267-aaa4-554d-b444-72a4c9aaddc9"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I file a claim for a loved one who passed away due to medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Yes close family members can file a claim on behalf of a deceased relative if the death was due to medical negligence.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9fb8e903-9241-5797-b61f-2d0a7af202ee"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What evidence is required to prove medical negligence?",
    "Answer": "Evidence such as medical records expert testimonies and a detailed account of the events leading to the harm are required.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "13c82033-13a7-5494-bdc7-6926652d64be"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can a claim be made for psychological harm resulting from negligent care?",
    "Answer": "Yes psychological harm such as PTSD caused by negligent care can be grounds for a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e258f8f2-370c-541f-a6a2-eb7bddb13f37"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can a healthcare provider be liable for failing to obtain informed consent?",
    "Answer": "Yes failing to obtain informed consent before a procedure can be a breach of duty of care if it leads to patient harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ad354d7e-1850-5885-8626-aac08b64203c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What constitutes a breach of duty in the context of follow-up care?",
    "Answer": "A breach occurs when a healthcare provider fails to provide adequate follow-up care leading to patient harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2902a8c9-7b87-52c4-98d1-8a6347f9ceaa"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How does misdiagnosis relate to a breach of duty of care?",
    "Answer": "A misdiagnosis can be considered a breach if it falls below the accepted standard of care and results in harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "42612505-244b-567b-8a91-83d084002d90"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Is failure to refer a patient to a specialist a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Yes if the failure to refer a patient to a specialist leads to harm it can be considered a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e6316dd4-e188-5736-b2c7-63407e41edd3"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What is the importance of patient safety protocols in preventing a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Patient safety protocols are critical in ensuring care meets required standards and failure to follow them can constitute a breach.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "16161cbf-5ba8-5997-8170-3ca5e90c3861"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How is causation affected if multiple healthcare providers were involved?",
    "Answer": "Causation can still be established if it can be shown that the harm resulted directly from the negligence of any involved provider.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "eaf95d61-89c7-592d-8514-3ff9eeeaa3e4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What role does the \"but for\" test play in establishing causation?",
    "Answer": "The \"but for\" test helps determine if the harm would have occurred if not for the negligent act or omission.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "0b0fbec3-5de8-5afd-b9fe-d6afe2be1480"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be established if the harm was a known risk?",
    "Answer": "Causation may be harder to prove if the harm was a known risk unless it can be shown that negligence increased the risk.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "045ffa5c-8514-58fd-b3e3-32a787f889ee"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How do time delays impact proving causation in negligence claims?",
    "Answer": "Time delays can complicate proving causation but if the delay directly worsened the condition causation can be established.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8dcad343-9e31-525e-a64b-aed0827a4372"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What is the role of a second opinion in establishing causation?",
    "Answer": "A second opinion can provide critical evidence in establishing that the initial care was negligent and caused harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "a5329576-bc1e-5475-b9c8-fad24ef3c792"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period apply to claims for minors?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period for minors typically begins when they turn 18 giving them until they are 21 to file a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8040cf48-b8a5-5a79-92d9-96dc72192ecb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can the limitation period be extended in cases involving mental incapacity?",
    "Answer": "Yes the limitation period can be extended if the claimant is mentally incapacitated and unable to manage their own affairs.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7693ab28-be78-5ba7-b6bc-2f54cbf8edda"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What happens if the limitation period has expired?",
    "Answer": "If the limitation period has expired the claim may be barred unless the court grants an extension based on special circumstances.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "44c9f51e-c8dc-5daa-9e49-82fceac0c6e8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can I still claim if the injury occurred abroad?",
    "Answer": "Yes but the limitation period and legal process may vary depending on the country where the injury occurred.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2b5aa15d-6801-5705-b227-d7e8c4a625c5"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period differ for different types of claims?",
    "Answer": "Different types of claims may have different limitation periods so it's essential to seek legal advice as soon as possible.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "88d7699c-2dea-505d-aded-f0b0d7860eee"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How are damages for future medical expenses calculated?",
    "Answer": "Future medical expenses are calculated based on the expected cost of care and treatment over the patient\u2019s lifetime.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9f97e6a0-3787-52d1-b0d5-59464f78fe36"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can compensation include the cost of assistive devices?",
    "Answer": "Yes compensation can cover the cost of assistive devices like wheelchairs prosthetics or hearing aids if they are needed due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "27a83b0b-f23b-5f54-9b0f-40630892e356"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What factors influence the amount of general damages awarded?",
    "Answer": "Factors include the severity of the injury the impact on the claimant\u2019s life and comparable cases in legal precedent.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e868d0b7-e74d-550b-bdd4-02e72da08632"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How is compensation for pain and suffering determined?",
    "Answer": "Compensation for pain and suffering is based on the severity of the pain and its impact on the claimant's quality of life.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "b7343da1-f9dc-5f3d-a777-2fd51af8274c"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can special damages include the cost of home modifications?",
    "Answer": "Yes special damages can include the cost of necessary home modifications such as ramps or widened doorways due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5cb15723-1ab7-5f86-97d2-af7c77335649"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What must be included in a report to the DWP regarding compensation?",
    "Answer": "The report must include details of the injury the compensation amount and how it might affect the claimant\u2019s benefit entitlements.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e33f8ff5-880a-520f-bdaf-73837e05e7ed"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How does the Compensation Recovery Unit (CRU) interact with claims?",
    "Answer": "The CRU recovers benefits paid due to the injury from the compensation awarded ensuring no double compensation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e1d28a9b-c022-5e05-ba0d-a08fb0b52819"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Can you challenge the amount the DWP seeks to recover?",
    "Answer": "Yes you can challenge the recovery amount if you believe it does not accurately reflect the benefits received due to the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c19ea7c2-af3b-549d-93a3-3056f1e55240"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What is the impact of compensation on means-tested benefits?",
    "Answer": "Compensation may reduce or eliminate eligibility for means-tested benefits depending on the amount awarded.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "397d99f1-3076-50fa-aa8c-5760f4360f25"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How do I ensure compliance with DWP reporting requirements in a claim?",
    "Answer": "Working with a solicitor can help ensure that all necessary information is reported to the DWP accurately and in a timely manner.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "45ee65e0-3544-520d-970f-696c096d7dd1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme help in resolving claims?",
    "Answer": "The scheme facilitates quicker resolution of claims often without the need for prolonged litigation by encouraging early settlement.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "bf3d110f-1f42-5fe0-abba-0d70300f6db9"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What are the benefits of early notification for claimants?",
    "Answer": "Benefits include faster resolution less stress and potentially higher compensation due to reduced legal costs.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2dcc36cf-c433-56e0-a7d3-49e4aaf54101"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Can claims under the Early Notification Scheme be escalated to court?",
    "Answer": "Yes if a settlement is not reached claims can still be taken to court under the standard legal process.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "439b13fe-02a4-567b-8ebf-70f5364e40db"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does early notification impact the investigation process?",
    "Answer": "Early notification allows for a more thorough and timely investigation which can lead to a more accurate and fair outcome.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "0648cd76-f6f3-5000-b48c-6a60e5a3736d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What role do medical experts play in the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "Medical experts provide early assessments that can help establish the validity of a claim and the extent of the harm caused.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "0f97a9fa-98c2-5279-b014-87e83d4d93c6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What legal actions have been taken regarding vaginal mesh complications?",
    "Answer": "Several class actions and individual lawsuits have been filed leading to significant compensation for affected patients.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4fa03dda-96da-5946-aec9-e220a7ebb574"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "How do you prove negligence in a vaginal mesh claim?",
    "Answer": "Negligence can be proven by showing that the risks were not adequately communicated or that the mesh was improperly implanted.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "30870fcb-028a-537a-99b3-5dd3e86ef677"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can you claim for lost wages due to complications from vaginal mesh?",
    "Answer": "Yes lost wages can be claimed if complications from the mesh led to an inability to work.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "cc9bd3fa-ba7d-5967-9a4b-fc328531e3f4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What is the process for obtaining medical records for a vaginal mesh claim?",
    "Answer": "You can request your medical records from the hospital or clinic where the mesh was implanted to support your claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7353dbc1-82b8-5088-be70-46d8e4159990"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can I join a group claim if I was affected by vaginal mesh?",
    "Answer": "Yes many patients affected by vaginal mesh complications join group claims to strengthen their case and share legal costs.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4360b516-10ac-54ca-8b06-0f3c0ceed40b"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What should I do if I suspect harm from sodium valproate during pregnancy?",
    "Answer": "Seek legal advice immediately to explore your options for making a claim and obtaining compensation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "14f7bcf9-087e-575c-9aa4-f5cae01fd9c8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "How has the regulation of sodium valproate changed over time?",
    "Answer": "Regulations have become stricter requiring clear warnings about the risks associated with sodium valproate especially during pregnancy.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8c017545-6ffb-5a84-9c0a-560ac5ce5687"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Can you claim for the cost of special education due to sodium valproate exposure?",
    "Answer": "Yes compensation can include the cost of special education if the exposure led to developmental disorders requiring such services.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "79ef3ee8-d32f-581c-8010-2ba7da8a6e29"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What evidence is needed to support a sodium valproate claim?",
    "Answer": "Evidence such as medical records prescription details and expert testimony linking the drug to the harm is essential.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "d615efe0-58fe-5400-b463-a9887d231f07"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Are there support groups for those affected by sodium valproate?",
    "Answer": "Yes several support groups exist to help affected families connect share experiences and pursue claims together.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "378ff9c3-aa37-512b-8b5b-69f601f96279"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I claim if my condition worsened due to delayed treatment?",
    "Answer": "Yes if the delay in treatment directly led to a worsening of your condition you may be eligible to claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "014cb1d2-50c4-5dd2-b18f-e9cda1a8cb67"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "What if I wasn't informed of all the treatment risks?",
    "Answer": "You may be able to claim if it can be shown that lack of informed consent contributed to the harm you suffered.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "a98775d2-cfc1-5101-b761-f2491bd72164"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I claim for poor aftercare following surgery?",
    "Answer": "Yes if the poor aftercare led to complications or a worsening of your condition you may be eligible to make a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7bb19693-8da8-52cf-8cb6-f7ae728c648e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Is it possible to claim if I didn't follow all medical advice?",
    "Answer": "Yes but it may be more challenging to claim if it can be shown that not following medical advice contributed to the harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "43d45927-d42b-5f99-8dd2-21773deb2bf1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Eligibility",
    "Question": "Can I file a claim if my doctor was acting under emergency conditions?",
    "Answer": "Claims under emergency conditions are possible but may be more complex as the standard of care may differ in emergencies.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8a6f36a4-8140-5cbc-a3c0-da69a7855a88"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "How does a failure to diagnose impact duty of care?",
    "Answer": "A failure to diagnose a condition can be a breach of duty if it results in harm that could have been avoided with proper diagnosis.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2d837fbf-902a-576e-b699-0ecbf5487494"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Is a miscommunication between healthcare providers a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Yes miscommunication that leads to patient harm can be considered a breach of duty of care.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "64d4eec4-9a9a-5f9b-a85d-a88ddfeb60b6"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can incorrect patient records lead to a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Yes if incorrect records result in inappropriate treatment or harm it could be considered a breach of duty.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ada6e44b-98f6-5d0a-b63d-66ccf9ec2888"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "What is the role of clinical guidelines in determining a breach of duty?",
    "Answer": "Clinical guidelines set the standard of care and failure to follow them can be evidence of a breach of duty.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7be542b5-1be8-5d53-b438-e2da5bb3e9f1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Duty of Care",
    "Question": "Can a breach of duty occur if a procedure is performed by an inexperienced doctor?",
    "Answer": "Yes especially if the lack of experience directly contributes to patient harm it can be considered a breach of duty.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ebf42573-5eb1-56fa-a02c-c2ad70aadfac"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How does pre-existing condition affect causation in a negligence claim?",
    "Answer": "Causation can still be proven if it\u2019s shown that the negligence exacerbated or worsened a pre-existing condition.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "8a01d0d5-b318-5046-ae40-6c9b490ac6c4"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can a hospital's systemic issues be considered in establishing causation?",
    "Answer": "Yes if systemic issues like understaffing contributed to the harm they can be relevant to establishing causation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2bdf3868-297c-5c8e-8189-a493ab5d1fb7"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "What is the \"material contribution\" test in causation?",
    "Answer": "This test is used when multiple factors contributed to harm and it must be shown that the negligence made a material contribution.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5869fb82-a39f-5a0f-86d8-1cd0f1c6e0fc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "How do expert medical opinions influence causation?",
    "Answer": "Expert opinions are critical in proving that the harm resulted directly from the negligent act or omission.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "a67bcdbd-f38a-564c-b6a5-e82898d21c36"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Causation",
    "Question": "Can causation be proven if there are multiple possible causes of harm?",
    "Answer": "Yes but it may require demonstrating that the negligent act was the most probable cause of the harm.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "40b9228e-45fa-5e69-9c6b-320f31f3140f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What is the limitation period for claims involving children?",
    "Answer": "The limitation period typically starts when the child turns 18 giving them until they are 21 to file a claim.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3d38bbd9-3214-5bd2-a1c8-6037506e0450"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Are there any exceptions to the three-year limitation rule?",
    "Answer": "Yes exceptions include cases of mental incapacity or if the injury was not discovered until later.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "5d187c6d-5206-507c-8586-4a6a07d6ad27"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "How does the limitation period apply to overseas treatment claims?",
    "Answer": "Limitation periods for overseas treatment may vary depending on the laws of the country where the treatment occurred.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "98bbfcaf-5504-5971-83f3-efcdab6e70b8"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "Can I extend the limitation period if the injury was only discovered recently?",
    "Answer": "Yes in some cases the limitation period can be extended if the injury was not discovered until later.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "929d150e-0001-595e-a4a9-992de5488170"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Limitation",
    "Question": "What happens if I miss the limitation period for filing a claim?",
    "Answer": "If the limitation period is missed you may be unable to pursue the claim unless the court grants an extension under special circumstances.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "10baf005-42ec-5ef0-b516-c2a41c349c97"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How are future loss of earnings calculated in damages?",
    "Answer": "Future loss of earnings is calculated based on expected career progression salary increases and retirement age.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "78c827ed-2941-5278-a650-25fec2786732"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can I claim for psychological impact in addition to physical injuries?",
    "Answer": "Yes damages can include compensation for psychological impact such as anxiety depression or PTSD resulting from the injury.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4ad6d8d4-5968-5c45-8ad6-559760cefa75"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "What are aggravated damages?",
    "Answer": "Aggravated damages are awarded when the defendant\u2019s conduct has been particularly egregious or has caused additional distress.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "3a48a9c3-d15d-5ed0-8d1e-f1c647246668"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "How do you prove special damages in a claim?",
    "Answer": "Special damages must be proven with receipts invoices and other documentation showing the actual financial loss incurred.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "879f5692-f203-5d26-88f9-ae8b0e47ce89"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Damages",
    "Question": "Can damages include compensation for loss of amenity?",
    "Answer": "Yes loss of amenity or the inability to enjoy life as before is a key factor in determining general damages.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "e9cf5d99-117a-54d8-b3be-2cf76f3fc69d"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "When should a claim be reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "A claim should be reported to the DWP as soon as compensation is awarded or agreed upon to ensure compliance with benefit regulations. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "6f036ab1-679b-524c-9061-5984bdcc5ffa"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What happens if a claim is not reported to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Failing to report a claim to the DWP can lead to penalties including the recovery of benefits paid due to the injury. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "a7e614b1-9fd2-50a7-995d-9ac7bb652e8a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "How does the DWP calculate the amount to recover from compensation?",
    "Answer": "The DWP calculates the amount based on the benefits paid to the claimant due to the injury and deducts it from the compensation. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "61576079-6b8a-5fff-a4d5-4397b0d1e5c0"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "Can I negotiate the amount the DWP seeks to recover?",
    "Answer": "In some cases it may be possible to negotiate or challenge the recovery amount if you believe it is incorrect. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "ee50c3b8-a799-528d-8ac8-a85b28fcea9e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "DWP Reporting",
    "Question": "What information is required when reporting a claim to the DWP?",
    "Answer": "Details of the injury compensation amount and the impact on any benefits the claimant receives must be provided to the DWP. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "403e9c11-0814-5b64-bc7e-2a20442bf380"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What types of claims are suitable for the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "Claims involving severe birth injuries such as cerebral palsy are typically suitable for early notification. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2f352390-b041-583e-93a5-8ec4c2291585"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme reduce legal costs?",
    "Answer": "The scheme encourages early settlement reducing the need for lengthy litigation and associated legal costs. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "6ab8a406-9197-5777-863b-a17a6b68d79a"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "Can the Early Notification Scheme be used for non-birth-related claims?",
    "Answer": "No the scheme is specifically designed for early resolution of birth-related injury claims. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "9d257e69-93df-5f4d-9401-8e8bb60f0559"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "How does the Early Notification Scheme benefit the NHS?",
    "Answer": "The scheme helps the NHS address and resolve claims more quickly reducing the potential for costly legal battles. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4b07f4b8-c7ec-5f8d-ba3f-c1bc449457cc"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Early Notification Scheme",
    "Question": "What is the role of the NHS Resolution in the Early Notification Scheme?",
    "Answer": "NHS Resolution manages the scheme ensuring claims are handled efficiently and fairly with a focus on early settlement. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "4c69d032-7d11-5eb8-8a41-bf7bdc0b27cb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What compensation is available for complications from vaginal mesh?",
    "Answer": "Compensation may include damages for pain and suffering lost wages and medical costs related to the complications. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "de84f47c-8b0f-57b3-abdf-53a7d391050e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "How do you start a claim for vaginal mesh complications?",
    "Answer": "Start by consulting a solicitor specializing in medical negligence to assess your case and gather necessary medical records. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c654f68c-bcbb-5b7b-ad38-359dffae866f"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What are the long-term effects of vaginal mesh complications?",
    "Answer": "Long-term effects can include chronic pain infection and the need for further surgeries to remove or repair the mesh. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "7b378bc4-cbe2-52f3-b81b-241312bee837"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "Can you claim for emotional distress caused by vaginal mesh complications?",
    "Answer": "Yes emotional distress is a recognized component of damages and can be included in your compensation claim. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "cc0da810-3d7b-5a6b-a10d-4839342b6827"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Vaginal Mesh Claims",
    "Question": "What legal precedents exist for vaginal mesh claims?",
    "Answer": "Several high-profile cases have set precedents resulting in substantial compensation for those affected by mesh complications. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "c94db562-0e72-5a0e-9b28-ee102219c4a1"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What are the legal implications of prescribing sodium valproate during pregnancy?",
    "Answer": "Prescribing sodium valproate during pregnancy without proper warnings may be considered negligent if it results in harm to the child. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "2ebc3d93-bae3-5022-9274-612758e98203"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Can fathers of children affected by sodium valproate exposure claim compensation?",
    "Answer": "Yes fathers can also claim compensation if their child was harmed by sodium valproate exposure during pregnancy. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "567c8f1c-5a5c-5cb9-861d-e8e03fa9650e"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What role do support groups play in sodium valproate claims?",
    "Answer": "Support groups provide resources information and collective action opportunities for those affected by sodium valproate. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "40c97665-a8f5-5003-bad5-411c4d5acffb"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "Can you claim for future care needs due to sodium valproate exposure?",
    "Answer": "Yes future care needs including specialized education and medical treatment can be included in the compensation claim. ",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "f69cc75b-f570-5a14-9d92-0365b6085a00"
  },
  {
    "Category": "Sodium Valproate Claims",
    "Question": "What steps should be taken if harm from sodium valproate is suspected?",
    "Answer": "Seek legal advice immediately to explore your options for making a claim and obtaining compensation.",
    "Section": "nhs claim benefits",
    "id": "fdaf9eb1-efab-5bbb-b98a-c01d3e06576f"
  }
]